grantham.edu 2008-06-15

# Privacy Policy | Grantham University

## Web Privacy Statement

Grantham University is committed to protecting your privacy when you visit our Web sites, so we want you to know what information we collect when you visit one of our sites, how we use that information, and how you can update it. The University reserves the right to append or otherwise modify this Privacy Statement at any time, so please re-visit this page occasionally to check for updates. 

### Information We Collect 

We collect various types of information from our visitors so we can adjust our site to meet our users’ needs and expectations. Some of this information is collected automatically through cookies, and other information is collected when you register for any of our online services. 

### Information Collected Automatically 

The types of information your browser or Internet session automatically sends us each time you visit one of our sites, which we automatically collect, includes: 

  * Your browser, e.g., Internet Explorer, Netscape Navigator. 
  * Your Internet domain, e.g., AOL, Netcom, Earthlink, etc. 
  * Your computer’s operating system, e.g., Windows, Macintosh, UNIX, Linux. 
  * Your navigation path, i.e., the URLs of where you come to our site from, which of our pages you visit, and where you go as you leave. 
  * Your IP address. 

This information lets us see how users are finding our sites, and it tells us which pages are visited the most often so we can make our Web sites more useful. 

### Information You Provide to Us 

In addition to the information automatically collected by your browser, we also collect information that you provide to us when you register for an online service, order merchandise from us, or request information regarding one of our programs. 

  * Application/Registration Information: Information provided in applying for employment or admission to the University or in registering for courses is used solely for those purposes, and is protected accordingly. Data collected during these processes, either collectively or individually, may be shared with third party government agencies as required by law. Details can be obtained from either the Office of Admissions and Records or the Office of Human Resources. 
  * Name and Address Information: We maintain a database of names and addresses (e-mail and paper mail) of people who may be interested in hearing about new and upcoming events, publications, or various University activities. Names on this list come from requests for materials and requests for other information or services. We do not share this list with organizations outside of Grantham University. 
  * Payment Information: In the course of providing our students with automated services, Grantham University receives some personal payment information in the form of checks and credit cards. It is the policy of the University to protect all information provided to us by all participants through the payment process. Grantham University does not sell or share any non-public personal information or student lists with any third party, except as may be necessary to complete a transaction in the ordinary course of business, or as required under an applicable law, or with your concurrent notice and approval. 

Grantham University provides links to other Web sites. When you leave the Grantham University Web site please be aware that Grantham University is not responsible for the privacy practices of these other sites. 

As an institution of higher learning, Grantham University adheres to the rules and regulations as set forth by Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA). 

### Your Rights, Our Obligations 

Grantham University does not sell or rent any personal data submitted by visitors to our site to any third parties. The University respects the privacy of users visiting our University sites and will abide by all applicable laws concerning the release of personal information. On occasion we may use certain directory information that we have collected to send you information about products and services, or updates and other information we think may be of interest to you. If you tell us that you do not wish to have this information used as a basis for further contact with you, we will respect your wishes. Please contact Grantham University to request your name and address be removed from our lists. If you do not want to receive our e-mail marketing, please submit a request to have your e-mail address removed at the following e-mail address: [unsubcribe@grantham.edu](mailto:unsubcribe@grantham.edu). 

Other than directory information, data you provide to us as you use Grantham University’s Web site will be held in strict confidence by the University and will be used for University purposes only. The University may share aggregate information about our users with advertisers, business partners, sponsors and other third parties. However, the individual information you provide us within the Grantham University Web site will be known only to you and the University. We will not share your personal data with anyone else, except as may be required by law. 

### How To Update Your Information 

Our student services site provide you with the option of changing and modifying information you have previously provided to us. To change or modify your student services account information, please call 1.800.955.2527 toll free. 

### Our Security Measures 

Our University Web sites have security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. We utilize industry standard SSL encryption when accepting your credit card information during the online ordering process, as well as whenever we ask you to login to any of the University’s online student services, such as our Library or the Student Web site. 

### Definitions 

#### Cookies

Data created by a Web server that is stored on a user’s computer. It provides a way for the Web site to keep track of a user’s patterns and preferences and, with the cooperation of the Web browser, to store them on the user’s own hard disk. 

The cookies contain a range of URLs (Web addresses) for which they are valid. When the browser encounters those URLs again, it sends those specific cookies to the Web server. For example, if a user’s ID were stored as a cookie, it would save that person from typing in the same information all over again when accessing that service for the second and subsequent time during the same browser session. 

You can opt out of the use of cookies by having your browser disable cookies or warn you before accepting a cookie. Look for the cookie options in your browser in the Options or Preferences menu. 

NOTE: If you disable cookies in your browser, you will not be able to access any of the University’s secured Web sites.

#### IP ( Internet Protocol ) Address 

This is the address of a computer attached to a TCP/IP network. Every client and server station must have a unique IP address. Client workstations have either a permanent address or one that is dynamically assigned for each dial-up session. IP addresses are written as four sets of numbers separated by periods; for example, 204.171.64.2. 

#### Browser Session 

A browser session is defined as the period of time a browser is in consecutive use. The session begins when you open the browser and ends when you close it. When you reopen the browser, you begin a new session. 

#### SSL Encryption ( Secure Sockets Layer ) 

The leading security protocol on the Internet. When a SSL session is started, the browser sends its public key to the server so that the server can securely send a secret key to the browser. The browser and server exchange data via secret key encryption during that session. We also use SSL encryption whenever we display your personal information (e.g., name and address, scheduled courses, grades). 

#### URL ( Uniform Resource Locator ) 

An Internet address. URLs are used to locate sites on the Internet and to navigate between sites and pages within sites. The URL for Grantham University is [http://www.grantham.edu](http://www.grantham.edu/).
